I'm not going to lie. I feel a little
bit guilty that yesterday was all me
talking. Well, I have good news today.
Less talking, more doing. Welcome to
your first yellow day, the first day of
working with products. Welcome to the
day when we go through cursor, copilot,
codeex, and anti-gravity. Let's get
started. So, the purpose for today is
for me to show you a number of the
different agentic coding products out
there and also take it as an opportunity
to show you some of the way that you go
about doing what we call vibe coding.
And I want to give you some some
principles to keep in mind throughout
today. First of them is that everything
I show you today is going to be optional
for you. I want you to have a feel for
the different agentic AI coding
platforms there are out there. It
doesn't mean that you need to use all of
them. You might want to if you want to
have that hands-on experience. It might
be completely fine for you just to see
me doing it and pick up the differences
between them. So, it's optional.
Download them, install them, and use
them if you wish. But otherwise, you can
pick the one you like. It might be
cursor. It might be GitHub Copilot. It
might be Claude Code that we're really
going to dig into next week. And that
can be the one that you stick with. You
don't need to do them all. And then the
second point to mention is that you are
going to get different results to me. I
say your results may vary. Your results
will vary and I'm going to be using some
versions of models and you might be on
different models. You might be on
cheaper models if you don't want to
spend so much. You might be on free
models. You might be on something
completely different. So your results
might be different. Go with what you
have. And uh yeah, take it take it as
part of the experience to see different
results. And the single most important
principle for today is not to get
frustrated. If things don't go well and
the the agent starts delivering
nonsense, which can happen, particularly
if you're getting downgraded to cheaper
models, then the trick is first of all,
be patient. It's easy for me to say it.
I I lose my patience myself sometimes.
Try and stay patient. Give the the agent
feedback on what's happening. And then
if in doubt, simplify simplify simplify.
reduce the scope of the problem, make it
simpler, get something to work, and then
build from there. Simplification is such
a big trick to keep in mind. And if you
can't get it to work, you can always
just delete and start everything again
and just give it a second shot from from
the beginning. And if that doesn't work,
you can always skip that particular
product and go to the next product and
see if that works. There's so many
options today. Most important of all is
to have fun with it. We're going to be
playing with tons of different products.
We're going to be seeing very different
results. It's really interesting. You
should enjoy today a lot. And with that,
let's go straight to the lab. I would
like you to open back up cursor again.
Cursor that we already had some
experience with. Go back into cursor and
I will see you there. And this is what
cursor should look like when you open
it. And if not, you go to file and you
go to new window. And then you should
see this. And I would like you to start
by going back to the instant project
that we already worked on. It might pop
it up as one of the things here or you
might need to press open project and go
into it. But once you have, you should
be back in instant. This look familiar.
This is what we did before. This is
where we're going to begin. Now, what I
now like you to do is to find the course
resources. If you don't already have
them to hand, they are linked in in many
of the first few videos in Udemy. You
also should have got a link in your in
your welcome email when you enrolled.
Bring up the course resources and and
find this section. So, you're following
along there. And the first thing you
should see is a link to the website for
NodeJS Node. And if you don't already
have Node installed on your system,
that's what we're going to do right now.
And this this is Node's uh landing page
right here. It is nodejs.org.
And when you come here, I want you to
click on download, which if you haven't
done it before is where we will download
Node. So here on the download page, you
will see that you can get Node to
install it on a Mac or on a PC. It's
defaulted to the Mac settings right
here. This using these commands is the
way to do it on a Mac. Don't worry about
where we run them. We'll do that in just
a second together. And if you're on a
PC, then then you can if you if you're
on Windows and you have something called
Chocolatey. If you've used that before,
you can just install it this way. But
also, you could come down here, go to
Windows, pick x64, and then use this to
get a a normal Windows installer. Use
any of these techniques to install Node.
If you have any problems with it, then
you should just message me or look in
the course resources in case I've got
some suggestions there. And when it
comes to running commands, if you want
to run these commands for Windows or Mac
rather than running this installer, the
place that you can do that is back here
in cursor. When you're looking at
cursor, you can go to the view menu and
select terminal. And up will come this
little screen here, a little terminal.
And this is where you can punch in the
commands to install node. And once
you've done it, once you've installed
node, you can then bring up a new
terminal by pressing like the plus
button here. You get a new terminal. And
in here, you should be able to type node
minus minus version. And you should get
back a version. Maybe it's the same as
me. Maybe you've got a more recent
version. Anything after 22 is is great.
And at this point, you are set with
NodeJS. Any problems with it, uh, drop
me a message, a Q&A in Udemy or an
email, and I'll help out. Or look in the
course resources for tips. Now, we're
just going to spend a few moments now in
this terminal. And some of you use
terminals all the time. For some of you,
this might be a bit new. And it's
nothing to be afraid of, even if it does
look a little bit like it's it's
something hung over from the 80s. Uh,
but here we are. What we're looking at
here is we're looking within the
directory that's called instant that we
created before that's in perhaps in a
projects directory. And the way you can
see that is you can type this command
pwd which stands for print working
directory and it tells you where you
are. And I am in users ed projects
instant which makes sense. And if you're
on a PC it will look a bit different.
You'll have backslashes instead of
forward slashes but it's going to be
much the same kind of thing. You're in
instant. And uh that's a fine place to
be if you're working on instant but but
we're going to work on something
different. So what I want to do is I
want to go up one directory to the
projects directory. And the way you do
that is you type cd for change directory
and then a space and then dot dot. And I
know most of you know this already, but
then when I do that, if I now do pwd,
you can see that sure enough, I am in
the parent directory. I'm in the
projects directory where I have uh all
of my projects, quite a few of them.
Okay. And if you look in the course
resources, you'll see that I have a a
repository, a repo on GitHub that I now
want to bring down locally so that that
that repo is on your computer. And
there's a simple way to do it. It's a
git clone command. I'm going to type git
clone. And then I'm going to paste in
the link to that repo. There it is right
here. It'll also be on the course
resources. age https
github.com/ed-donor/canban.git.
You know what a canban is? That's what
we're about to be doing. So I run this
and bam, it happens. I've done it. We
now have a directory. I can I can go
into it. You don't need to, but I can go
cd canban.
And there we go. We are in canban. If I
do pwd, then you will see I am in users
ed projects cambban. and you will be in
some different thing probably with
backslashes maybe but basically the same
idea you will have canban set up that is
the project we'll be working on now okay
so now to switch over from instant to
this new project called cananban you go
to cursor's file menu and you say new
window and this screen comes up remember
this screen and now you press open
project okay fair enough here we go and
now you go into into your project so you
navigate your way to your your projects
directory and you'll see that there is
canban here it is and then you go into
canban by double clicking and then you
press the open button to have launched
the cananban project and you'll know
because it will say canban here and it
will say kanban in block capitals up on
the top left and that means we've had
success we are now in the canban project
great it's time for us to start [__]